<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:18:37-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Someone? Really? Maybe I'll Email First.]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2011/03/31/call-someone-really-maybe-ill-email-first/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-31T13:36:37-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2011/03/31/call-someone-really-maybe-ill-email-first</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because I'm trying to make sure Baby J is cultured, intelligent and sophisticated, we generally listen to CBC Radio 1 in the mornings.</p>

<p>(Well, really, it's because we listen to it first thing for the traffic updates, and I'm generally too lazy to turn it over afterwards).</p>

<p>Jian Ghomeshi hosts "<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/q/">Q</a>", which is self-described as "an energetic daily arts, culture and entertainment magazine that takes you on a smart and surprising ride, interviewing personalities and tackling the cultural issues that matter."  It features a wide variety of topics and guests - most famously, the show featured Billy Bob Thornton, who was on the show to promote his band but got... a bit upset that Jian dared to mention his OTHER career.  <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJWS6qyy7bw">Here's the YouTube video of what went down then</a>.</p>

<p>But an interview yesterday caught my attention, with journalist Pamela Paul about the state of the personal and business call these days. <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/q/blog/2011/03/29/are-out-of-the-blue-phone-calls-intrusive/"> You can listen to the interview here</a>.  But the general gist is that, for most adults in the working world:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Personal calls have been largely replaced with texts, emails or instant messages with the exception of a predictable set of intimate contacts (parents, spouses, children).  The ring of an unexpected call can cause anxiety - the first thought is "What's wrong?".  Non-routine personal calls are normally set up as "phone dates" in advance, and the negotiation is done over electronic means.</p></li>
<li><p>Business calls are also rare without first setting up the groundwork via email; sending a quick note via email is the expected, indicating you plan to call at a certain time to discuss a certain topic, with the basics of the discussion contained within.</p></li>
<li><p>No one checks their voicemail when they have Caller ID.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>This describes my communication style to the letter.  "Back in the day", I was a bit of a phone addict, like most teenage girls of my era.  I was even slow to catch on to the SMS trend.  These days the only people I actually call, and who call me, without some electronic communication first, are my mother and in-laws.  Like the interviewer suggests, at home I think of phone calls as almost intrusive -  Why are you calling me?  I'm busy (probably not, but still...)!  Send a note and I'll respond on my own time!  Unless it's something urgent, I much prefer the one-way communication methods of text, email or IM, and their non-threatening nature.  Not sure if you want to respond?  I don't know if you got the message, so you can take your time.  One thing we DON'T have in our household is Caller ID, the philosophy being "If you didn't leave a message, it mustn't have been important."</p>

<p>At work, I normally will send an email to a contact outlining as many details of an impending call as possible, to avoid miscommunication of important facts and details as much as I am trying to avoid the actual call itself.  Business calls have their own set of rules with respect to small talk and negotiation, and I haven't learned all the rules yet.  If we can hammer out the facts via email, that's just fine by me.  If we can't do that, I'd prefer a face-to-face meeting over an hour-long phone chat.</p>

<p>For a while, I thought my behaviour and thoughts regarding phone communications were anti-social and unusual (I'm finding more and more that I am an introvert, but more on that some other time).  So this interview made me feel better about myself.  But do I feel better about where our society is headed?  Will we lose the art of conversation, or gain time once spent chatting inanely about the weather and vacations?  Should the ring of my home phone bring on panic instead of curiosity?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh Me Nerves: Email Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2008/12/12/oh-me-nerves-email-edition/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-12T09:55:50-03:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2008/12/12/oh-me-nerves-email-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In the second of an ongoing series of posts, Id like to share with you, dear reader (singular), what boils my blood, what grinds my gears, what gets my goat.  Some may think Im easy going but there are many things that get on my nerves.  And this is one of them.</em></p>

<p>I send and receive a number of emails over the run of the week.  Work email, IEEE email, social emails, responding to emails telling me how to enlarge things and get money from a dead guy's Swiss bank account.  It's all good.  I'm a big fan of email over actually talking to people.  But not all emails are created equally.  Not even emails written by the same person on the same day.  And some email habits really drive me nuts.  Maybe I'm old-school.  Let me share with you some of my email driven angst:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Emails sent without subjects. </strong>I cringe everytime Gmail says (no subject) for the subject to an email I've received.  I don't CARE if the email is a one-liner asking me about my weekend plans.  Or if you only email me on one topic, therefore there's no need to explicitly state the subject.  I don't care if you forgot.  The subject line is there to be filled in.  I like to know what's inside.  I like to look back on the subject and determine what your email was about.  And usually, if I'm replying to a no-subject email, I fill one in.  You may not notice, but it makes me a little happier.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Emails with more than one topic.</strong> I'm a bit... OCD about filing my email.  I love Gmail and how it allows me to tag one email with multiple labels.  But I'd prefer not to have to do that.  Personally, I'd prefer two separate emails with well-crafted subject lines.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Emails not written coherently. </strong>It's a informal form of communication, but it's only communication if both parties are communicating.  If I can't understand you, it's not really communicating.  I'm not talking good grammar, or full sentences.  Re-read your email from the point of view of one who did not write it... can you understand what you are trying to get across?</p></li>
<li><p><strong>SPAM from myself.</strong> Do you get this?  It's happening a lot on my school account.  And I'm not seeing a damn cent from it.  Argh.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>That is all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Looney's Clean]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2007/01/18/the-looneys-clean/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-18T18:21:28-03:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2007/01/18/the-looneys-clean</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>sigh</em> I'm a little disappointed that Canada ISN'T the smart little sister, but still the dumb young kid brother...</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/RTGAM.20070118.wspyy0118/BNStory/International/home">Official report of Canada 'spy' coins not true: U.S.</a></h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Always Thought that Polar Bear Looked Suspicious, and Don't Get Me Started on the Loon...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2007/01/11/i-always-thought-that-polar-bear-looked-suspicious-and-dont-get-me-started-on-the-loon/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-11T09:02:34-03:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2007/01/11/i-always-thought-that-polar-bear-looked-suspicious-and-dont-get-me-started-on-the-loon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I gotta say, I'm a little proud (and a tad weirded out) when I read this story:</p>

<p><a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2007/US/01/11/spy.coins.ap/index.html?eref=rss_topstories">Pocketful of Espionage: Beware the Spy Coin</a>
Bet the US never thought we had it in us, hey?  Kind of like when you find out your little sister's been reading your diary and replacing that hair you put across page 42 to detect intruders...</p>

<p>Now, I must go to Tim Horton's and spend whatever change I have... can't be too careful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presto Chango]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/10/10/presto-chango/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-10T20:09:19-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/10/10/presto-chango</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TaDa!  I've changed to WordPress (I'm a band-wagon jumper).  I'm working to set it up the way I like it, so please bear with me.  The gallery is coming back, promise, and maybe with some new pics!!  Hopefully I can get her back to where I like her.. but I DO enjoy the theme I'm using (not mine nor my pic).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
