<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Memes | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/categories/memes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:12:58-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, that sounds about right...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2007/03/11/hey-that-sounds-about-right/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-11T16:39:42-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2007/03/11/hey-that-sounds-about-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>You Are 28 Years Old</strong></p>

<p><img src="http://images.blogthings.com/whatagequiz/cake.jpg" alt="" /> Under 12: You are a kid at heart. You still have an optimistic life view - and you look at the world with awe.13-19: You are a teenager at heart. You question authority and are still trying to find your place in this world.</p>

<p>20-29: You are a twentysomething at heart. You feel excited about what's to come... love, work, and new experiences.</p>

<p>30-39: You are a thirtysomething at heart. You've had a taste of success and true love, but you want more!</p>

<p>40+: You are a mature adult. You've been through most of the ups and downs of life already. Now you get to sit back and relax.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.blogthings.com/whatagequiz/">What Age Do You Act?</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six Degrees of Blog Separation]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/03/six-degrees-of-blog-separation/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-03T11:16:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/03/six-degrees-of-blog-separation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're all aware by now that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_degrees_of_separation">everyone on earth is connected to anyone else to by five intermediary people</a>.  So, if you've got some time on your hands, try this...</p>

<p>Start with a link on your blog that leads to the website/blog of someone YOU KNOW... no celebs unless you could stop them at the supermarket and have a real chat with them.  That's link #1.  From their page, select a link of someone (a) you do not already have linked on your page, preferably (b) that you don't know and if possible (c) is someone THEY know (I know, I'm making this far too complicated).  That's link #2.  And so it continues, until you get to link #6.</p>

<p>It's both easier and harder than you'd think.  Some people don't have links on their site to friends (does this mean they don't have friends? Hmm...). Some people have the same links that I do.  And <a href="http://www.chriskidney.com">some people</a> haven't updated in forever, thus I've discounted them.</p>

<p>I took the following path:
Link #1 - Me to <a href="http://www.earlwoodman.com/">Earl</a>
Link #2 - Earl to <a href="http://mind-boggles.blogspot.com/">Nancy</a>
Link #3 - Nancy to <a href="http://vickyth.wordpress.com/">Vicky</a>
Link #4 - Vicky to <a href="http://mumblingmonkey.blogspot.com/">Mumbling Monkey</a>
Link #5 - Monkey to <a href="http://pateys.nf.ca/weblog">Heather</a>
Link #6 - Heather to <a href="http://www.savemouse.com/wordpress/">Mouse</a>, a blogging whippet-like dog who has bad spelling but I'm sure means well, and now has a  CUNTINNUS DAG FIDIR!  He is happy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Nerd Score....]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/28/my-nerd-score/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-28T07:09:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/28/my-nerd-score</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nerdtests.com/ft_nq.php?im"><img src="http://www.nerdtests.com/images/ft/nq.php?val=1777" alt="I am nerdier than 92% of all people. Are you nerdier? Click here to find out!" /></a></p>

<p>Lord help you if you're nerdier.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Quotations...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/17/random-quotations/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-17T07:38:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/17/random-quotations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took the idea from <a href="http://applpolisher.blogspot.com/2006/08/random-hitching-post.html">Div</a>, though I must thank her for not tagging me or anyone in particular.</p>

<p>So this game goes like this:
1. Go <a href="http://www.quotationspage.com/random.php3">here</a>
2. Pick 5 quotes that "you think reflect who you are or what you believe"
3. Post them</p>

<p>Did I ever tell you about a nasty habit that flight attendants pick up on the job? We learn to always keep smiling, even when we're out of Bloody Mary Mix. - Eric Wald, View From The Top, 2003</p>

<p>Believe it or not, I was once a smiley happy person.  Lately, not so much (as my sister-in-law points out every so often).  But I think (a) it's not a bad thing to keep a positive outlook, and (b) it's wrong to fake happy all the time - you've got to let people know your thoughts and emotions every once in a while... you're not an island like Paul Simon.</p>

<p>Nothing is really work unless you would rather be doing something else. - James M. Barrie (1860 - 1937)</p>

<p>True.  Some days, the things that are work are the things I'm not getting paid to do.  Trying to stick more to things I enjoy nd stay away from the other stuff... but I'd always rather be sleeping.</p>

<p>My mother drew a distinction between achievement and success. She said that 'achievement is the knowledge that you have studied and worked hard and done the best that is in you. Success is being praised by others, and that's nice, too, but not as important or satisfying. Always aim for achievement and forget about success.' - Helen Hayes (1900 - 1993)</p>

<p>I really like this one.  Satisfaction and pride should come from within, not from what outsiders think!  I hope to achieve many things... but success can kiss my butt. :)</p>

<p>Do something. If it doesn't work, do something else. No idea is too crazy. - Jim Hightower, The New York Times, March 9, 1986</p>

<p>Also know as "how to finish a Masters in Engineering".</p>

<p>I have always found that mercy bears richer fruits than strict justice. - Abraham Lincoln (1809 - 1865)</p>

<p>If only more modern world leaders had the same thought...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does this mean I'm out of the beagle pack?]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/06/30/does-this-mean-im-out-of-the-beagle-pack/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-30T08:18:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/06/30/does-this-mean-im-out-of-the-beagle-pack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You Are A Labrador Retriever</p>

<p><img src="http://www.ideafetch.ca/en/FunStuff/BreedImages/Dogs/d1.gif" alt="A Labrador Retriever" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.ideafetch.ca/en/FunStuff/DogBreedQuiz.asp">What Dog Breed Are You?</a> at <a href="http://www.ideafetch.ca/">Idea Fetch</a></p>

<p>Also check out <a href="http://www.usanetwork.com/sports/westminsterdogshow/dogfun/profiler/">this link</a>, where you can do another test.  I did it four times, and each time the questions were slightly different.  Judging from the results I'm half Siberian Husky (forgetful, loyal and goofy) and Golden Retriever (loyal, lovable).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
