<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:18:37-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presto Chango]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/10/10/presto-chango/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-10T20:09:19-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/10/10/presto-chango</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TaDa!  I've changed to WordPress (I'm a band-wagon jumper).  I'm working to set it up the way I like it, so please bear with me.  The gallery is coming back, promise, and maybe with some new pics!!  Hopefully I can get her back to where I like her.. but I DO enjoy the theme I'm using (not mine nor my pic).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You're all CRAZY...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/26/youre-all-crazy/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-26T10:17:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/26/youre-all-crazy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>... if you think I deleted my last blog posting.</p>

<p>:P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time for a Change...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/04/time-for-a-change/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-04T11:49:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/04/time-for-a-change</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I realized that I'm no longer feeling green-and-orange, the old template colours.  I'm a bit more muted... a little more introspective.  Looking across the proverbial ocean at the future.  So, I've made some changes.  Feel free to find errors, critique something, tell me you like it, whatever.  I <em>know</em> I need some sort of separator line between postings.. that irks me.  But generally, I'm okay with it.</p>

<p>And I've updated my Random Links.... though I must admit, the sidebar's a little wonky right now, especially in Internet Explorer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not the Real Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/15/not-the-real-thing/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-15T14:06:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/15/not-the-real-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought this article, <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/2006/0515/p13s01-stct.html">It's All About Me</a>, was interesting, especially since I've been misunderstood recently, not in email, but in message boards and blogs I regularly comment on... and well, my own blog too.  As stated in the article,</p>

<blockquote><p>First and foremost, e-mail lacks cues like facial expression
and tone of voice. That makes it difficult for recipients to
decode meaning well.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which is why every email, blog posting and message board posting should be accompanied by a face shot... preferably of the poster, but if one isn't available you can use a substitute.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/face-755676.JPG"><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/face-748886.JPG" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
