<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Weight Loss | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/categories/weight-loss/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:25:20-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q1 Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2007/03/26/q1-update/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-26T16:26:40-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2007/03/26/q1-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.padre.ca/house/blog/">House</a>'s recent recap of his resolutions made me go back to <a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2007/01/01/another-new-year-another-set-of-resolutions/">my own</a>... and I realize I'm not gettin' very far.  Here's my update...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I've been on and off the "healthy living" bandwagon since the start of the year, and as such I won't be making my 15lb. loss mark before heading to see <a href="http://www.geoffholden.com">Geoff </a>in <a href="http://www.frommers.com/destinations/sanfrancisco/">Northern California</a>.  But despite work and IEEE travel between now and then, I will get back on it and stick with it.  I've got a bridesmaid dress to look good for <a href="http://www.ourcelebrationsite.ca/25august2007/index.cfm">in August</a>, and other things to get in shape for...</p></li>
<li><p><em>sigh</em> I've been doing decently with keeping my extra-curricular activities organized, though I haven't kept it all to one night (I had designated Monday night as such).  But I need to do more to get on top of some of the bigger commitments, ie IEEE Canada.  Please, someone, nag me (not you House... I'm saving you for something else)... Randy?</p></li>
<li><p>Academics... huh?  What's dat?  Ya, I've done little/nothing in the past three months in this area.  I've wanted to, but I haven't put the energy into it.  And to be honest, I'm not gonna until at least after vacation.... but barring any extra work that comes up, I expect to be done my draft by the end of the year, and plan to use some of my four weeks annual leave to make that happen.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>In other news, I spent the St. Patrick's Day weekend in Boston at an IEEE meeting.  The meetings went well, socializing was fun (though I did not drink any green beer... instead I had a seafood hangover).  The trip home was a bit of a pain - delayed out of Boston meant landing in Montreal when the plane to St. John's was supposedly taking off, rushed through customs and was told by the ticket lady (who wrangled us boarding passes after our flight had been "closed") to run run run all the way to the gate.  Little old out of shape Lori (see first bullet point) is in extreme debt to Rob, who ran ahead to let them know we were coming... only to find that the plane had just gotten to the gate.  Argh.  So we made the flight with plenty of time, though my luggage didn't, it came the next day.  Pics (of Boston, not of my luggage) to be posted soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wesley's Woes and Weight Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/14/wesleys-woes-and-weight-update/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-14T14:28:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/14/wesleys-woes-and-weight-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been a busy sort of week for my little puppy boy.  It started off great last weekend - the <a href="http://www.beaglepaws.com">Beagle Paws</a> reunion was Sunday at Mundy Pond Visitors' Centre.  We obviously all went.  April barked quite a lot, but was generally well-behaved (she may be mellowing).  Wesley was the social butterfly, sniffing and being sniffed, and had the record (slowest) time for the obstacle course!  We left happy.</p>

<p>On the way home, I had to stop at work to pick something up.  It was while I ran to my office that Brian noticed blood in the back seat.  Further inspection revealed that Wesley was bleeding - more than a little bit.  The source of the blood was detected (cut on the pad of his back right paw) and B did his best to make him comfy while we tried to track down a vet, which is no small task here on a Sunday.  After calling their emergency line, we drove towards and sat in the lot of the vet clinic until someone happened to be leaving.  But the bleeding was stopped by then, things seemed okay, so we were sent home and told to come back during normal business hours.</p>

<p>Which we did, first thing Monday morning.  Dr. Laite saw him and his wound (which by now was doing okay) and deemed him okay... which he seemed to be.  But the gosh-darn bandage she put on came off Monday afternoon, and the bleeding stated again.  And kept going, everytime he managed to get the bandage off or we needed to change it.</p>

<p>Back to the vet.  This time, it bled when she unwrapped it.  A lot.  There was a concern he may have a clotting problem (think hemophila), but tests for that came back normal (thank goodness).  The next step was surgery, to determine if maybe something was in his wound.</p>

<p>So yesterday, my little puppy boy went in for surgery to see what was the cause of the blood.  Turns out there was nothing in the wound, but whatever made the cut nicked an artery.  Ouch.  That was taken care of quickly, and at the same time we had a lump removed form the side of his paw.</p>

<p>So now he is recovering.  His exercise is limited for the next 10 days (like that matters to him, he'd be sleeping anyway), he's got some pills to ward off infection, and he'll be fine.  As will the rest of us. :)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/100_1980-706639.JPG"><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/100_1980-701623.JPG" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Weight Update:  Lost another pound this week, meaning I'm down 16.6 lbs since January.  Not a lot but better than up!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weight Loss Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/05/weight-loss-update/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-05T16:30:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/07/05/weight-loss-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven't talked about this for a while.  I'm still trying to lose weight and be healthier.  I'm currently 15.6 lbs lighter today than I was in the beginning of January.  I still have 20-30 lbs to go to be at a "happy", healthy weight.  I'm still working out (sporadically), still tracking points, still drinking litres and litres of water.  I'll keep ya posted!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[None]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/04/03/139/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-03T09:48:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/04/03/139</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don't want to ask the question too loudly for fear Mother Nature will hear me and dump snow on me.  But the weekend was great for weather, and the snow is melting... it's a mood booster to be sure!  Next winter I'm buying a sun lamp or investing in some tanning sessions (for my well-being, not for my looks).</p>

<p>My weight-loss has remained rather stale the past few weeks.  No gains (yay!) but no losses (boo!).  I'm being extra vigilant with the exercise and eating this week.  See how that goes.</p>

<p>Countdown to Australia is 11 days and ticking!  That's another mood-booster.  I'm actually looking forward to all that time sitting on a plane, doing nothing.</p>

<p>I'll try to more intelligent/interesting.. perhaps comment on world peace (spent some time reading about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rachel_Corrie">Rachel Corrie</a> this weekend... the world is so unfair) or <a href="http://www.extremeironing.com/">Extreme Ironing</a>.  But for now I'll go get lunch!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
