<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TV | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/categories/tv/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:18:37-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feel-good TV - Hoarders]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2010/02/10/feel-good-tv-hoarders/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-10T19:13:18-03:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2010/02/10/feel-good-tv-hoarders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having some time before bed and not wanting to do anything useful or productive, I turned on the TV.  I came across the show "Hoarders". I've heard about it but have never seen it until now.  Gotta say, it makes me feel a little better about the state of our basement. :)</p>

<p>But I can somewhat relate to the whole hoarding problem.  Has someone (or your inner voice) made you feel guilty for letting food go to waste?  Or throwing away something that you might use in future? Have you bought something you didn't really like or didn't really need because it was an amazing bargain?  I've done all these at some point.  There is no real logic behind it.  Now take those minor feelings, multiply them, and you've got yourself a hoarder.</p>

<p>I don't think I'll make "Hoarders" a regular part of my TV watching, but it's a good reminder to keep buying and "keeping" in check.  And to clean a bit more of the basement.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Would Do If I Had the Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/12/things-i-would-do-if-i-had-the-time/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-12T07:46:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/12/things-i-would-do-if-i-had-the-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Note:  Despite it being Monday, I'm in a generally good mood... so don't take this post as some sort of depressive negativity overwhelmed rant...)</p>

<p>I, like a lot of other people, wish I had more free time.  But, at the very least until I finsh my thesis (let's not go there, shall we?) and get past September's IEEE GOLD Congress, and knock off a few more "To-Dos" from my list, I probably won't.  But when I do get the time, there a number of things I'd like to do.  I know a lot of them, reasonably won't happen until I retire or something, unless I end up in a body-cast for some reason... but feel free to suggest other things!</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn to run without feeling like an idiot</li>
<li>Watch all episodes, marathon-style, of "Scrubs", "Farscape", and "Sex and the City"</li>
<li>Re-read "The Lord of the Rings" and "Harry Potter" books</li>
<li>Read the books that I've bought but haven't read yet</li>
<li>Take the dogs on a long car ride followed by a good hike</li>
<li>Camp more</li>
<li>Learn to golf (or at least hit a golf bal somewhat consistently in a predicted direction farther than five feet)</li>
<li>Learn to use the fancy-pants camera we have, more than just the pre-defined settings</li>
<li>Walk around St. John's and Mount Pearl and actually take pictures without feeling like an idiot or a tourist</li>
<li>Take a conversational French course</li>
<li>Drive to Gros Morne National Park and spend a week without contact</li>
<li>Visit family I haven't seen in a while</li>
<li>Work on my family tree</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Weeks to Get There, One to Enjoy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/31/three-weeks-to-get-there-one-to-enjoy/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-31T19:51:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/31/three-weeks-to-get-there-one-to-enjoy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Actually just said by a (former) celebrity Brandie Someone-or-Other in the Showcase Showdown of "The Price is Right" on "Gameshow Marathon", some sort of celebrity... well, gameshow marathon... "Is the trip by boat or by plane?".</p>

<p>The Showcase in question included a boat AND a trip to Sydney Australia.  Maybe she's one of three North Americans over the age of 20 who has never seen Bob Barker work his magic, and doesn't understand how the show works.  But dear Lord woman, I hope you aren't serious... a boat trip to Australia isn't a PRIZE, it's what the did to criminals a few hundred years back from England!</p>

<p>Generally speaking, it's funny to see people who probably haven't done their own grocery/furniture/anything shopping (well, paying for it) in years determine the cost of a couch or the Tums.  Thank god they have talent... or a good agent, or they'd be screwed.</p>

<p>Sorry... I'm kind of rambling.  As you were.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm All By Myself...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/21/im-all-by-myself/"/>
    <updated>2006-05-21T17:26:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/05/21/im-all-by-myself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was at the airport last night, but for once it was not me who was going somewhere.  Brian is in Oslo, Norway for the next ten days for work... so back here, it's just me and the puppies!  It's kinda weird to not have someone else in the house, and to be honest i'm not sure what I should be doing!  I've cooked, cleaned, went to the gym, spent quality time with the dogs... there's not much left to watch on TV since the season finales are happening.</p>

<p>Any good, clean, useful suggestions?  Otherwise I'm gonna have to work on my thesis...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
