<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Harry Potter | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/categories/harry-potter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:18:37-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My thoughts on Harry Potter, as voiced by someone else]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2007/07/22/my-thoughts-on-harry-potter-as-voiced-by-someone-else/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-22T10:24:02-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2007/07/22/my-thoughts-on-harry-potter-as-voiced-by-someone-else</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was one of many who lined up at Chapters on Friday evening to get my pre-ordered copy of <em>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows... </em>I've been counting down the days, spent the past few months re-reading the previous books for clues as to the fate of the wizarding world<em>.</em>  I devoured it Saturday, but not in the manner I've read the previous releases; I read it quickly in careful chunks, wanting to let what was happening sink in rather than letting events tangle and blur in my mind (because, not to give anything away to those waiting to read it, but it IS an action-packed book).  Some make fun of me for only reading every second word, and while that's not true, once my copy of the book returns back to me I will be re-reading at a more leisurely pace, to enjoy the company of characters I've watched grow and develop over a seven-year span.
<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/arts/books/potterseries.html">This article from CBC </a>perfectly fits my thoughts on the series and what it has meant in the bigger picture.  We even jumped into the series at the same time, and while we'll both miss Harry and the gang (my favorite has always been Hermoine, but not how she is portayed in the movies... the Hermoine I see when reading will always be the Hermoine I first pictured when reading), the series is over and that's that. But for a brief while, millions of Muggles have been simultaneously enthralled by a tale of external and internal struggle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm scared....]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/27/im-scared/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-27T06:56:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/27/im-scared</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don't want Harry to die.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/story/arts/national/2006/06/26/rowling-potter-deaths.html?ref=rss">Two characters to die in last 'Harry Potter' book: J.K. Rowling</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Would Do If I Had the Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/12/things-i-would-do-if-i-had-the-time/"/>
    <updated>2006-06-12T07:46:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/2006/06/12/things-i-would-do-if-i-had-the-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Note:  Despite it being Monday, I'm in a generally good mood... so don't take this post as some sort of depressive negativity overwhelmed rant...)</p>

<p>I, like a lot of other people, wish I had more free time.  But, at the very least until I finsh my thesis (let's not go there, shall we?) and get past September's IEEE GOLD Congress, and knock off a few more "To-Dos" from my list, I probably won't.  But when I do get the time, there a number of things I'd like to do.  I know a lot of them, reasonably won't happen until I retire or something, unless I end up in a body-cast for some reason... but feel free to suggest other things!</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn to run without feeling like an idiot</li>
<li>Watch all episodes, marathon-style, of "Scrubs", "Farscape", and "Sex and the City"</li>
<li>Re-read "The Lord of the Rings" and "Harry Potter" books</li>
<li>Read the books that I've bought but haven't read yet</li>
<li>Take the dogs on a long car ride followed by a good hike</li>
<li>Camp more</li>
<li>Learn to golf (or at least hit a golf bal somewhat consistently in a predicted direction farther than five feet)</li>
<li>Learn to use the fancy-pants camera we have, more than just the pre-defined settings</li>
<li>Walk around St. John's and Mount Pearl and actually take pictures without feeling like an idiot or a tourist</li>
<li>Take a conversational French course</li>
<li>Drive to Gros Morne National Park and spend a week without contact</li>
<li>Visit family I haven't seen in a while</li>
<li>Work on my family tree</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
