<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Random | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-16T22:46:17-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Love Fall]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/10/06/why-i-love-fall/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-06T21:01:12-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/10/06/why-i-love-fall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/fall-blog.jpg"><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/fall-blog-225x300.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>When I was younger, I always thought that Labour Day was the same as New Year's Day.  It didn't make sense that the new year officially started in January.  September was when the new school year begins, when my birthday happens, and when life resumes its normal pace after a  lazy summer.  And I loved all of that!!</p>

<p>I still love September, and I especially love the start of fall, my favorite season.  Why is fall my favorite season?</p>

<ol>
<li><p>The return of reasonable temperatures that are seasonally appropriate (I'm looking at you, June 2011).  I'm not one who enjoys extended periods of warmth.</p></li>
<li><p>Windy, rainy days that don't make you feel bad for staying home and watching a movie and enjoying some comfort food.</p></li>
<li><p>Wearing sweaters, skirts and tights.  I &lt;3 tights.</p></li>
<li><p>Walking the dog down a path framed with coloured leaves.</p></li>
<li><p>Labour Day, Thanksgiving, Remembrance Day. The long weekends!</p></li>
<li><p>An inevitable IEEE trip somewhere (this season there are two trips: Jersey City and Mississauga).</p></li>
<li><p>The start of school, classes, clinics, etc.</p></li>
<li><p>The return of loved TV shows and the start of new ones.</p></li>
<li><p>Winter is something to look forward to still, not swear at while in the middle of it.</p></li>
<li><p>Darker evenings mean an easier time getting Baby J to sleep, and darker mornings mean a tad more sleep. For now.</p></li>
<li><p>Planning for Christmas. Ya, I said it.</p></li>
<li><p>Hallowe'en! (Full disclosure: I've never been a huge fan of Hallowe'en, but having a kid makes it more fun this year.)</p></li>
<li><p>The return of the pumpkin spice latte at Starbucks, and knowing that Peppermint Mochas are coming soon!</p></li>
<li><p>Fall running. I don't like getting too sweaty, and hate wearing shorts when I run. Fall temperatures take care of that for me. :)</p></li>
<li><p>... SO many more things that can't be verbalized.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Birthday Nicole!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/25/happy-birthday-nicole/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-25T15:03:39-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/25/happy-birthday-nicole</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nicole, you must download this!</p>

<p>(Anyone else can too, but it's not your birthday.)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/MVI_4965.avi">MVI_4965</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Photo]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/19/random-photo/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-19T10:35:05-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/19/random-photo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/wpid-2011-05-18-15.48.29.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>Let's see if this works, shall we? A boy and his giraffe...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sitting Target (of Advertising)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/11/sitting-target-of-advertising/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T20:25:39-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/05/11/sitting-target-of-advertising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because I'm currently a SAHM (which I will blog about soon) of an almost 3 month old, and particularly because I am breastfeeding (which I also hope to share about), I spend a LOT of time sitting... Either feeding, napping, or just too zonked to do much else. And I do a fair amount of sitting with TV on.</p>

<p>For those who wonder, daytime TV is seriously lacking - talk shows, soaps, reruns (though Spike DOES show a lot of CSI, which I enjoy) are the typical fare. But the ads definitely target "older adults" (walk-in tub anyone?) and moms. And despite my self-proclaimed superior intelligence, I find myself affected by the ads in ways I wouldn't think of. I'm starting to care about how my house smells, and what germs are lurking because I'm not using the right anti-bacterial wipe. But besides pushing a certain product, advertising offers subliminal pushes as well. All the actors are, well, skinny, and well-dressed, with perfect kitchens and living rooms and gardens. And while I know they are actors on a set, some part of my brain is now more worried than ever before about these things and how inadequate my house and housekeeping skills are, and how I look (granted, I am carrying "baby weight"... Maybe I'll blog on that too). It makes no sense, yet it's getting to me!</p>

<p>I only hope that logic can continue to prevail, or that the weather stays good this spring and upcoming summer. I plan on switching off the TV and enjoying real life, commercial-free.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Have A Blog, Might As Well Use It!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/03/25/i-have-a-blog-might-as-well-use-it/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-25T14:07:09-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/03/25/i-have-a-blog-might-as-well-use-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm going to start blogging again... why?</p>

<ol>
<li><p> I have a lovely new little baby boy (let's call him Baby J), and need another outlet to describe just how lovely he is and post countless pics that are practically indistinguishable from each other.</p></li>
<li><p> As a result of (1), I am on maternity leave and have a lot more free  time than I used to... when I'm not eating bonbons and watching my soaps, of course. Wait, I can do that AND blog, because I can multi-task.</p></li>
<li><p>Partly as a result of (2), I don't chat with as many people who don't wear diapers as I used to (at least, I assume most of my co-workers and colleagues don't wear diapers. Note, I have nothing against people, young or old, who do wear diapers). I can't influence others with my intelligent opinions and witty insights in person, so I need to harass the general public via the internet.</p></li>
<li><p> Referencing (3), though I've tried, I can't be all that intelligent-sounding in 140 characters (a la Twitter). I'm hoping to sound more intelligent when allowed more words. Hence the move back to "rambling".</p></li>
<li><p>Because I secretly hope to someday get a book deal, or influence a movie plot, or at least get some free swag for shamelessly selling out and writing positive reviews for something... anything... I'm not picky.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
