<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Literature | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/categories/literature/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-16T22:46:17-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Woody]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/10/03/for-woody/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-03T10:11:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/10/03/for-woody</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/woody-735377.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>](http://www.lorihogan.com/uploaded_images/woody-737994.jpg)
A sunny Sunday, 10a.m.
I'm letting the dog out to pee again
She comes back in, I make some toast
A bang on the house, could it be a ghost?</p>

<p>I peer out the curtains; no damage done
My eyes adjust to the blinding sun
I look to the ground, and there I see
The cause of commotion, a downed birdie</p>

<p>I can only assume you were out for a spin
Enjoying the autumn, catching the wind
Unable to see with your eyes with the glare
That it was our front window in front of you there</p>

<p>I'm sorry I couldn't do much more to aid
I went out to see you but you got afraid
You tried to escape but with the injuries sustained
You could not go far, now you're no longer pained</p>

<p>But you were a Flicker, red, black and brown
A beautiful woodpecker, even when down
I hope life was good for you, hope you had friends
Sorry about the accident, No hard feelings, the End</p>

<p>(A <a href="http://www.enature.com/fieldguides/detail.asp?recnum=BD0427">Northern Flicker</a> flew into our front window Sunday morning... I felt bad, but what's a girl to do?)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Quotations...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/08/17/random-quotations/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-17T07:38:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/08/17/random-quotations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took the idea from <a href="http://applpolisher.blogspot.com/2006/08/random-hitching-post.html">Div</a>, though I must thank her for not tagging me or anyone in particular.</p>

<p>So this game goes like this:
1. Go <a href="http://www.quotationspage.com/random.php3">here</a>
2. Pick 5 quotes that "you think reflect who you are or what you believe"
3. Post them</p>

<p>Did I ever tell you about a nasty habit that flight attendants pick up on the job? We learn to always keep smiling, even when we're out of Bloody Mary Mix. - Eric Wald, View From The Top, 2003</p>

<p>Believe it or not, I was once a smiley happy person.  Lately, not so much (as my sister-in-law points out every so often).  But I think (a) it's not a bad thing to keep a positive outlook, and (b) it's wrong to fake happy all the time - you've got to let people know your thoughts and emotions every once in a while... you're not an island like Paul Simon.</p>

<p>Nothing is really work unless you would rather be doing something else. - James M. Barrie (1860 - 1937)</p>

<p>True.  Some days, the things that are work are the things I'm not getting paid to do.  Trying to stick more to things I enjoy nd stay away from the other stuff... but I'd always rather be sleeping.</p>

<p>My mother drew a distinction between achievement and success. She said that 'achievement is the knowledge that you have studied and worked hard and done the best that is in you. Success is being praised by others, and that's nice, too, but not as important or satisfying. Always aim for achievement and forget about success.' - Helen Hayes (1900 - 1993)</p>

<p>I really like this one.  Satisfaction and pride should come from within, not from what outsiders think!  I hope to achieve many things... but success can kiss my butt. :)</p>

<p>Do something. If it doesn't work, do something else. No idea is too crazy. - Jim Hightower, The New York Times, March 9, 1986</p>

<p>Also know as "how to finish a Masters in Engineering".</p>

<p>I have always found that mercy bears richer fruits than strict justice. - Abraham Lincoln (1809 - 1865)</p>

<p>If only more modern world leaders had the same thought...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
