<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T23:02:41-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://lhogan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six Months In...]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2011/08/25/six-months-in/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-25T09:38:04-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2011/08/25/six-months-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40.jpg"><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40-300x196.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40.jpg"></a>... and what do I have to show for it? A healthy, happy baby boy who seems to be reading the development charts and following them perfectly.  A dog who is a bit jealous, but is learning to live with less attention. An awesome hubby who has become an excellent, patient father. A house that's no cleaner or more organized than it ever was pre maternity leave, but that's okay, as long as the laundry gets done. A bit of a tan from those few sunny days we've had that I can stroll with Baby J.  A better appreciation for SAHMs and anyone undertaking childcare professionally.</p>

<p>... and what do I miss? Sleep (I'm getting some and I'm not complaining, just being honest). The ability to have a margarita without planning around it (breastfeeding is awesome is so many ways though). Work (yes, a bit). Travel (soon to be rectified, hopefully).</p>

<p>... and what surprises have there been? How quickly the months have gone by. How slow some days can seem. How interesting it can be to just watch Baby J from day to day. How much love and pride I can feel for my family. How a sunny day makes so much difference when you aren't in an office. How great coffee can be after a difficult night. How different things actually are. How little some other things have changed.</p>

<p>... and what do I have to work on for the next six months? Patience (especially at 5am). Organization. Taking advantage of those quiet moments to get things done or do nothing without feeling guilty. Reaching out and staying connected to friends. Learning to ask for help. Learning to say "No".</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I took my lamp for a walk today....]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2007/03/11/i-took-my-lamp-for-a-walk-today/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-11T14:15:57-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2007/03/11/i-took-my-lamp-for-a-walk-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wesley had surgery on Tuesday past, an aggressive treatment (<a href="http://www.marvistavet.com/html/body_lateral_ear_resection.html">lateral resection</a>) for an even more aggressive series of ear infections.  A check-up visit to the vet yesterday was positive; things are healing up nicely apparently.  But until he gets the stitches out on Friday, he must continue to wear the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabethan_collar">Elizabethan collar</a>, a.k.a. the lamp shade, to avoid any scratching that may disturb the healing process.  He's maneouvering decently these days, especially after Brian trimmed the cone.  But he still bumps into things and plows snow as he goes out to do his doggy business on the patio.  But he's not very happy having it on, as you can see below.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2007/03/widescreen.jpg" alt="widescreen.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Still Alive, Honest!]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/20/im-still-alive-honest/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T20:09:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/20/im-still-alive-honest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been busy lately.  The "start of fall" (which, yes, technically isn't until September 23 this year, but forever in my mind fall always starts once Labour Day has passed and school starts) always awakens a flurry of activity as we shake of the lazy hazy summer days.</p>

<p>Last weekend found me in Toronto hosting an IEEE workshop, this time for GOLD.  In my opinion and despite my best procrastination efforts, it went well, and I think most would agree.  I must definitely admit that I need some help in keeping track of time and keeping conversations on track.  And to learn that 5:00am is not the best time to do slides.  But... whatever.  No one got hurt.  The work's not over, not by a long shot.  But the pressure is less.</p>

<p>Work is interesting, though I sometimes feel isolated at my desk, programming and writing.  I like the company, like most of the people most of the time (there are always times when the best people get on your nerves, and there are some people who will always clash), and like the projects.</p>

<p>I leave it here for now.  Be good!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lethargy]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/05/lethargy/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-05T18:10:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/09/05/lethargy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is wrong with me?  If I let me, I would collapse into a pile of sleepy goodness.  I've been like that all weekend (I know it's no longer the weekend).  Is it the flu?  Is autumn weaving its way into my psyche?</p>

<p>Maybe I'll sleep on it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Nerd Score....]]></title>
    <link href="http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/28/my-nerd-score/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-28T07:09:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://lhogan.github.com/blog/2006/08/28/my-nerd-score</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nerdtests.com/ft_nq.php?im"><img src="http://www.nerdtests.com/images/ft/nq.php?val=1777" alt="I am nerdier than 92% of all people. Are you nerdier? Click here to find out!" /></a></p>

<p>Lord help you if you're nerdier.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
