<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-16T22:46:17-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Chance?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/09/27/the-last-chance/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-27T19:27:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/09/27/the-last-chance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, must get this out of the way before starting the post.</p>

<p>Zach Braff is dreamy.</p>

<p>Okay, let's continue.  Last night I took in the movie "The Last Kiss" with B, Nikki, Kerry and Carla (who is the only one of us without a blog... jump on the bandwagon!).  I'm a big fan of Zach Braff (see above statement), of Scrubs, of the last movie I saw him in, Garden State, which he also directed.  I'm also a fan of Crash, the Academy Award winning movie cco-written by Paul Haggis, who wrote this adaptation of a 2001 Spanish movie.  I think Rachel Bilson, from The O.C. (which, I must admit, I've seen maybe half an episode), is a cutie.  Thus, it seem only fair I like this movie.</p>

<p>And I did, for the most part.  Zach plays the part of Michael, a 29 year old architect (pet peeve - the ratio of architects on TV/movies compared ot the number present in real life is way to disproportionate... why aren't there more engineers in pop culture?) who is about to be a daddy.  He lives with his girlriend/babymommy Jenna (played by Jacinda Barrett, who to me seemed almost too mature for her role), who we gather is a PhD student in something-or-other (that's not important I guess... a commentary on the roles women play, or am I reading too much in there?), but is afraid of marriage.  At a friend's wedding he chats up a young hottie Kim (Rachel Bilson), and admits he's in a crisis... and things play out from there.  I don't want to say too much, but you can probably guess what happens.</p>

<p>I think the movie deals with a lot of issues that many people my age are facing (whether they realize it or wish to admit it)right now - growing up, becoming committed (in relationships, not in the psych ward), buying property, having kids, etc. etc. when you really don't feel old enough for it.  I can definitely relate to that.  Ten years ago, I figured by the time I got to where I am right now (turned 27 a week and a half ago, celebrated our second anniversary two days ago, own a house and two dogs), I'd feel more mature.  I'd act more mature.  But nope... most days I feel like an imposter, acting like an adult and hoping no one will catch on and ground me for a month for drinking and staying out so late.</p>

<p>So, I'd suggest seeing it.  But it's just as good watched curled up on the couch than in the theatre.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chocolate and movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/09/20/chocolate-and-movies/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-20T20:51:00-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2006/09/20/chocolate-and-movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one's for <a href="http://www.applpolisher.blogspot.com">Divinity</a>, who hooked me on the <a href="http://applpolisher.blogspot.com/2005/11/not-my-forte.html">Virgin Digital-sponsored band photo</a>.  It's an "M&M; masterpiece" that contains references to 50 "dark movies" you must find.</p>

<p>If anyone is interested, we can start a list of solutions...</p>

<p><a href="http://us.mms.com/us/dark/index.jsp">Here it is!</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
