<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Baby J | Random Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/categories/baby-j/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-16T22:46:17-03:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lori Hogan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six Months In...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/08/25/six-months-in/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-25T09:38:04-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/08/25/six-months-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40.jpg"><img src="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40-300x196.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.lorihogan.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2011-08-10-10.22.40.jpg"></a>... and what do I have to show for it? A healthy, happy baby boy who seems to be reading the development charts and following them perfectly.  A dog who is a bit jealous, but is learning to live with less attention. An awesome hubby who has become an excellent, patient father. A house that's no cleaner or more organized than it ever was pre maternity leave, but that's okay, as long as the laundry gets done. A bit of a tan from those few sunny days we've had that I can stroll with Baby J.  A better appreciation for SAHMs and anyone undertaking childcare professionally.</p>

<p>... and what do I miss? Sleep (I'm getting some and I'm not complaining, just being honest). The ability to have a margarita without planning around it (breastfeeding is awesome is so many ways though). Work (yes, a bit). Travel (soon to be rectified, hopefully).</p>

<p>... and what surprises have there been? How quickly the months have gone by. How slow some days can seem. How interesting it can be to just watch Baby J from day to day. How much love and pride I can feel for my family. How a sunny day makes so much difference when you aren't in an office. How great coffee can be after a difficult night. How different things actually are. How little some other things have changed.</p>

<p>... and what do I have to work on for the next six months? Patience (especially at 5am). Organization. Taking advantage of those quiet moments to get things done or do nothing without feeling guilty. Reaching out and staying connected to friends. Learning to ask for help. Learning to say "No".</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Separation Anxiety, or Lack Thereof]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/04/08/separation-anxiety-or-lack-thereof/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-08T14:50:04-02:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.lorihogan.com/2011/04/08/separation-anxiety-or-lack-thereof</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don't want to brag <em>too</em> much, but I went out TWO nights last weekend. On Friday night I was honored to be a judge for some Senior ECE student presentations, and Brian stayed home with Baby J. On Saturday night, Brian and I went to a movie ("Source Code", which I enjoyed, but not the topic of conversation), and the grandparents spent a few hours basking in his glow.</p>

<p>I have no hesitation in leaving Baby J for a few hours, providing he's in capable hands (which he certainly was in the above cases).  I've heard of new parents who go months before leaving their child for a social evening. I'm far too logical for that. I mean, I wouldn't be going too far or for very long (not that breastfeeding would allow that) stop they'd less of a chance of missing an important development, and in case of emergency there's not much more I can do that Nan can't.</p>

<p>Not that I'm dissing those who can't bear to part with their little people. I kind of envy their resolve. And not that I don't question <em>my</em> bond with Baby J when I can go out for a few hours and come home to a happy baby who didn't notice I was gone. But I'm okay with that.</p>

<p>And I'm not completely rational. Please don't ask when we're moving him to his crib. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
